sansa.com 2010-05-24

# Privacy Policy

At SanDisk Corporation, we believe it is important to protect the privacy of our customers and guests. We know that you care about how your personal information is collected, updated, used and shared; and we want to help you make knowledgeable choices about the information you provide to us.

This Privacy Policy explains and summarizes how SanDisk Corporation and the SanDisk group of companies:

  * collect
  * use
  * and protect

your personal information as you interact with us online and through our customer and technical support services. 

This Privacy Policy applies to SanDisk Corporation, the web site located at www.sandisk.com, SanDisk operated web sites and SanDisk affiliates (collectively "SanDisk"). SanDisk affiliates include entities owned or controlled by SanDisk Corporation. In some cases, this Privacy Policy may be tailored to account for variances in law in a particular country. However, this policy is intended to be global in nature. If you are visiting from outside the United States there may be special rules or limitations on your use of this web site or other SanDisk operated web sites.

**By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information by SanDisk consistent with applicable data protection law and this policy.**

This policy explains:

  * What information SanDisk gathers from you.  
  * How SanDisk uses the personal information you share with us and that we learn about you because of our relationship.  
  * How SanDisk uses "cookies" and "IP Addresses".  
  * What personal information, if any, SanDisk may share about you and the conditions we use to protect your information if it must be shared.  
  * What kind of security measures SanDisk takes to protect your information from accidental loss or disclosure and how SanDisk will inform you in the event of a security breach.  
  * The circumstances under which you can you access personal information you share with SanDisk and have that information corrected, restrict SanDisk's use of that information or, even have it removed from our records.  
  * Other things you should know about privacy and SanDisk.

**COLLECTED INFORMATION AND USAGE**

SanDisk collects and uses information you provide to us including information obtained from your use of this web site. We are not in the business of selling information about you. SanDisk does not share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We may use or share your personal information (e.g., name, address, telephone number and e-mail address) where it is necessary for us to complete a transaction or do something that you have asked us to do.

  * For example, we might need to provide your name, address, phone number or email to one of our vendors so that they can process and fulfill your product return or replacement.
  * We might also refer your personal information to another manufacturer so that they can provide you with technical assistance you request for their product which you may be using in conjunction with one of our products.  
  * SanDisk employees, agents and service providers who need to access personal information you have provided to fulfill their responsibilities may do so consistent with SanDisk policies that limit access to this type of information.

SanDisk's vendors and suppliers may process your personal data under the direction and control of SanDisk. Whenever we may need to share your personal information, we try to provide you with the information you need to make informed reasonable choices and we manage your information consistent with applicable privacy law.

SanDisk collects and uses personal information from you in several ways:

  * **Web Site Usage.** SanDisk, or SanDisk vendors and suppliers, may observe your activities, preferences, and transactional data (such as your IP address and browser type) as well as pages you have viewed during your use of this web site. While we may collect or log this information, we do not identify you or match this non-personal information with your other personal information. We may use this collected or logged information to diagnose web site technical problems, or to facilitate your use of the site. SanDisk, or one of our vendors or suppliers, also may use this information to track aggregate traffic patterns throughout this web site.    
  * **E-Commerce**. You may be asked to share personal information such as your name, address and telephone number in order to complete a transaction. When you purchase a SanDisk product online you may be asked for information needed to complete your order, contact you to confirm the order and, provide related customer service. This information is used, for example, to effect your transactions, to create and share aggregate reports about these transactions, and to perform credit fraud screening services for transactions between you and SanDisk and/or our authorized service providers. When you buy direct from SanDisk these purchase transactions may be conducted through SanDisk vendors and suppliers including Digital River, Inc. ("Digital River"). Digital River and any other vendor or supplier engaged by SanDisk has their use of your personal information limited by this privacy policy, contractual restrictions and applicable law. In such cases, these distributors may be the merchant of record and the handling of any personal information you may provide to them shall also be subject to their privacy policy. To visit Digital River's privacy policy click [ here](http://corporate.digitalriver.com/store/driv/Corp/sectionName.company/subSectionName.corpPolicies/page.corpPolicies) **.** Please note that SanDisk (through Digital River or other vendors or suppliers) may limit the acceptance of orders to particular jurisdictions and as permitted by applicable law.  
  * **Product Registration & Technical Support.** SanDisk allows all purchasers of its products to register their products online. Personal information or data provided via online product registration forms is used to carry out the request, service or agreement for which the information is submitted. With your consent, we may also use the information you provide in online registration forms to notify you periodically about important changes to the web site (such as a change to this privacy policy or notice of a security breach), new SanDisk products and services, and special offers and contests that may be of interest to you. When you register, we ask for, among other things, your name, address, email, telephone number, type of product purchased and serial number or other product-identifying information, and date of purchase.

You are also invited to share other personal information about yourself through what is known as a "record." When you register your purchase with us and create a record, you are given control over and access to the personal information you provide in your record. We contract with a vendor to manage personal information you provide relating to product registration. Your record enables you to control what we know about you and lets you decide how and when we can communicate with you. Our vendor only processes your personal information as directed by SanDisk.   

  * **Optional Personal Information and Product Registration.  ** Some information or data you may place in your record is not required to register your products. Where completion of data fields in your record is required, these fields will be marked with an asterisk. Where you provide optional information, such as information about your interests and hobbies, SanDisk only uses this information on an aggregate basis to enable us to better understand our customers, develop new products, and improve our products and services.

SanDisk limits the access to and use of your personal information by our vendors and suppliers through the use of administrative, managerial and technical safeguards that are intended to enforce this privacy policy and assure compliance with applicable data protection law.

 Failure to register your product will not diminish the rights you have under the product warranty.

  * **Cookies.**  To the extent web site usage information is developed in connection with your IP address through session cookies, we will only use this information to facilitate your use of the SanDisk web site. Cookies are data files that are written onto your computer by a web site. At the end of your visit, the session cookies are removed.

SanDisk does not use cookies other than the session cookies identified. However, our service providers or vendors may use cookies in order to personalize your experiences and adapt the web site's functionality to your preferences. If you are visiting a URL other than SanDisk.com, or a SanDisk web site, including those hosted by our vendors including Digital River.com or other non-SanDisk URL, you should carefully review the cookie policy of these web sites. For users who register their SanDisk products through customers who purchase SanDisk products online through Digital River, and U.S. customers who purchase products online through shopsansa.com, cookies placed by Digital River or another SanDisk vendor or supplier (as applicable) will remain stored on your computer until you remove them.

You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to refuse receiving it, including those set by Digital River or, other SanDisk vendor or service provider. You should be aware that this may interfere with or make you unable to use certain functionality on web sites using cookies. For example, many web sites will ask your permission to use a cookie that will enable you to automatically log on to the web site. Disabling or removing cookies may require you to manually log on each time you wish to visit that web site. You may also delete cookies from your computer through your browser.   

  *   **Recruitment and Job Applications.** Residents of the United States may provide us with personal information through SanDisk.com. Personal information such as that contained on a resume or curriculum vitae, may be submitted in connection with a job application or inquiry. We may use this information throughout SanDisk (worldwide) for the purpose of employment consideration or your inquiry. We may keep your information on file for future consideration. _SanDisk does not accept applications for employment through its web sites from applicants outside the United States._  
  * **Children.** If under the relevant laws of the place where you are visiting this web site you are considered a minor (usually if you are under age 18), or otherwise would be required to have parent or guardian consent to share information with SanDisk, you should not send any information about yourself to us. For example, if you are a resident of the United States of America you should not submit information to SanDisk unless you are at least 13 years old.  If a person under 13 submits information through any part of the SanDisk web site, and we learn the person submitting the information is a child, we will attempt to delete this information as soon as possible. Because we do not knowingly collect any personal information from persons under 13, we do not use or disclose such information to third parties.   
  * **Public Areas.** Any information disclosed in public areas of the SanDisk web site will become public information. We cannot control the use of information disclosed in public forums, such as bulletin boards, blogs and chat rooms. You should exercise caution when disclosing information in these public areas and should refrain from disclosing your personal information. Content posted in public areas of the SanDisk web site, including advice and opinions, represents the views and is the responsibility of those who post the content.  SanDisk does not necessarily endorse, support, verify or agree with the content posted. If you have any questions or comments about any content on the SanDisk web site email:  [webmaster@sandisk.com.](mailto:webmaster@sandisk.com)

**WHEN SANDISK MAY SHARE COLLECTED INFORMATION**

As mentioned in the beginning of this policy, SanDisk may share your personal information within the SanDisk group to fulfill its obligations to you and operate its business consistent with this policy and applicable data protection law. SanDisk may also share your personal information with third parties in the following situations.

  * **SanDisk Vendors and Suppliers.** SanDisk works with vendors and suppliers to provide technical and customer support, shipping, credit card processing, product fulfillment or other services. SanDisk requires these vendors and suppliers to safeguard personal information you provide to us. To the extent it is necessary for these service providers to complete their contractual obligations to SanDisk, these third parties may have access to or process your personal information. SanDisk limits their use of your personal information to the purpose for which it was shared. SanDisk may sometimes permit our authorized service providers to have access to aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information. These transfers of aggregate statistics do not involve personal data.  
  * **Mergers, Acquisitions and Insolvency.**  If SanDisk should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, or if SanDisk should decide to buy, sell or reorganize some part or all of its business, SanDisk may be required to disclose your personal information, including information you have allowed us to see or use in your record, to prospective or actual purchasers or receive personal information from sellers. It is SanDisk's practice to seek appropriate protection for information disclosed or received in these types of transactions consistent with applicable data protection law.    
  * **As Required by Law and Other Extraordinary Disclosures** SanDisk may be required to disclose your personal information: (i) if it believes it is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (such as a court order, subpoena, search warrant, etc.) or other legal requirements of any governmental authority, (ii) would potentially mitigate our liability in an actual or potential lawsuit, (iii) is otherwise necessary to protect our rights or property, or (iv) is necessary to protect the legal rights or property of others.

**SPECIAL NOTICE TO INTERNATIONAL VISITORS AND CUSTOMERS**

Because SanDisk operates globally, we may transfer your personal information within our global operations to fulfill our obligations to you but always subject to the limitations of applicable data protection law and this policy. Privacy laws differ across the globe. To help visitors whose native language may not be English understand our privacy practices, we may provide special information on our privacy policies that may be applicable to these visitors in different languages here. If it is necessary for the purposes for which you have shared personal information with us for us to share your information within SanDisk's global operations, we will do so consistent with this policy. For example, necessary transfers of European customer personal information will be made consistent with Safe Harbor principles (see below).

**This web site is hosted in the United States.** SanDisk recognizes that many of our site's visitors may not use English as their primary language. Accordingly, in some instances we have made available versions of this web site in other languages here.

**If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, including those whose privacy laws may be more strict than U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States to SanDisk Corporation. By providing your personal data you consent to that transfer.**

**EU-** **U.S. Safe Harbor Adherence.** SanDisk adheres to the Safe Harbor principles agreed to by the United States and European Union relating to data protection. Information on the Safe Harbor may be found [here](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/).

Parts of this privacy policy may not apply to visitors from outside the United States because certain services are not offered to those outside the United States. For example, SanDisk may rely upon distributors to make SanDisk products available online. In such cases, these distributors may be the merchant of record and the handling of any personal information you may provide to them shall be subject to their privacy policy. Customer and technical support is available through this web site and via telephone worldwide. These services are provided in the United States subject to the Safe Harbor principles.

**STORAGE AND PERIOD OF HOLDING FOR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Unless otherwise requested by you, SanDisk will continue to keep the personal information you provided to us. If the reason for collecting your personal information no longer exists, we will delete the personal information at the appropriate required time if legally required by relevant applicable data protection law.

**SECURITY**

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure security on our systems. We use secure server software (SSL) and firewalls to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.

If SanDisk learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using this web site or providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of this site. SanDisk may post a notice on our web site if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the SanDisk.com web site. SanDisk may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at [privacy@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy@sandisk.com).

**LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY SITES AND CO-BRANDED WEB SITES**

This web site may contain links to third-party sites, however, please be aware that SanDisk is not responsible for and cannot control the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies for these other sites, as they may differ from ours.

This web site also contains links to co-branded web sites that may display SanDisk's logo and trademarks but which are maintained by third parties. Such web sites may be identified by the fact that they do not display a "sandisk.com" URL. Please read the privacy policy on the co-branded site for the applicable privacy practices relating to personal information collected via that site, as it may differ from this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies solely to personal information collected by SanDisk.

**CHANGES TO THIS POLICY BY SANDISK**

If in the future we change the SanDisk Privacy Policy, we will post the new policy on this web site. If this policy is somehow materially less restrictive or protective of your privacy than the current policy, we will not apply the less protective aspects of the revised policy to information you have previously provided to us without first obtaining your consent. If we have a way of contacting you electronically, we will do so in the way you have instructed us to obtain your consent. We reserve the right to change this policy in the future. Your continued use of this web site following a change in the privacy policy represents consent to the new policy to the fullest extent permitted by law.

We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy.

**MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS**

When you provide SanDisk with personal information, if you allow us, we may communicate with you by the method you choose about topics of your choosing. SanDisk seeks your consent to receive marketing communications from us when you provide your personal information.

**ACCESSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, MAKING CHANGES OR REQUESTING DELETION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You may at all times object or restrict SanDisk's use of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. You may also request access to, correction of or deletion of personal data. For instructions on changing any of your privacy preferences, accessing your information or for any privacy or data protection related question or concern click here for assistance.

Inquiries relating to updating or changing information you provided when purchasing SanDisk products directly online should be directed to Digital River, our online distributor. You may [ email](mailto:shopsandisksupport@sandisk.com?subject=Sandisk%20Store) Digital River for inquiries.

Inquiries relating to updating or changing information you provided when purchasing products online from the Sansa eStore (i.e. [www.shopsansa.com](http://www.shopsansa.com/))should be directed to <http://go.shopsansa.com/Help/CSContact.aspx>.

Please be aware that this Privacy Policy and the choices that you indicate when registering on this web site will not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to SanDisk or its vendors or business partners as part of other, separately-operated web sites or services.

Generally, when we contact you, we will try to provide you with an easy and convenient way to notify us if you would not like further similar communications.

If you have provided us with personal information not related to your purchase or registration of our products and would like to change or update your personal information, please [click here](https://reg.cheetahmail.com/regp?aid=445516089&n=400).

**CONTACTING SANDISK**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [privacy@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy@sandisk.com)

Postal Mail Address:  
SanDisk Corporation  
601 McCarthy Boulevard  
Milpitas, CA 95035  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
(408) 801-1000

If you have a privacy concern regarding SanDisk or this policy and if you cannot satisfactorily resolve it through the use of this web site you should then write to the SanDisk Data Controller identified below:

United States - [privacy@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy@sandisk.com)  
Latin America - [privacy-la@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy-la@sandisk.com)  
EMEA - [privacy-EMEA@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy-EMEA@sandisk.com)  
Japan - [privacy-japan@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy-japan@sandisk.com)  
Asia/Pacific - [privacy-asia@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy-asia@sandisk.com)  
Korea - [privacy-korea@sandisk.com](mailto:privacy-korea@sandisk.com)

In the event that we are still unable to resolve your concerns SanDisk is committed to cooperating to achieve a proper resolution of your privacy concerns.

Effective Date: 15 June 2009
